# CREATIVE DESIGNER / DEVELOPER

# **PERSONAL DETAILS**

Mobile (+61) 0421 644 329

Emailjohnny xu 1227@hotmail.comWebsitehttp://www.gaga-graphics.com

LinkedIn <a href="http://www.linkedin.com/in/johnnyxu">http://www.linkedin.com/in/johnnyxu</a>

Github <a href="https://github.com/gaga1227">https://github.com/gaga1227</a>

#### **OVERVIEW**

Creative Designer/Developer with more than 15 years of experience from digital agency, in-house and corporate environments in both Australia and China.

Talented and passionate about mobile, web and new technologies in digital design and development.

An organized perfectionist with great work ethic. Sharp attention to details and ambitions to create world-class works. Highly interested in working on mobile/web applications, responsive web design and digital entertainment with edge technologies.

# **SKILLS**

Creative	Development	<b>Application &amp; Others</b>
Art Direction	HTML5 / CSS3 / JS (ES6)	UI / UX Design
Digital Design (Web / Mobile)	React / Redux	Wireframing / Storyboarding
Responsive Web Design	AngularJS / Backbone.js	Information Architecture
Interactive Design	jQuery / Lodash	Web Accessibility Guidelines
Animation	Bootstrap / Foundation / Sass	Professional Scrum Master I
Print Design	Native Android	Sound / Video Editing
Illustration	Java / Node.js	Adobe Suite / Sketch
Sketching / Drawing	Unit Test / Automation UI Test	

Grunt / Gulp / Git / SVN

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

# Front-end Development Consultant (Contract)

Australia Post (OCT 2017 - Present) Melbourne, AUSTRALIA

Working on front-end experience enhancements for websites and web applications across different platforms for various stakeholders and domains from the business.

#### **Key Responsibilities**

- UI / Front-End Development for AEM components;
- Work with AEM team and support AEM components integration;
- Support and enhance existing and new front-end web applications;

# Software Developer, UI Developer

Sportsbet Pty Ltd (JUN 2014 - SEP 2017) Melbourne, AUSTRALIA

Worked on applications across desktop and mobile platforms from front-end web development to native Android app development, also with contributions to Back-End service APIs and applications.

#### **Key Responsibilities**

- UI / Front-End Development across desktop and mobile feature products;
- Part of the core team developing new native Android app;
- Part of the core team developed Punters Club;
- Create, maintain unit tests, automation UI tests and improve coverage;
- Work with UI/UX team to provide support and best UI solutions;

# Senior Interactive Developer, Digital Designer & Front-end Developer

Fraynework Limited (MAY 2011 - MAY 2014) Melbourne, AUSTRALIA

Worked on Responsive Web Design, Mobile Web Development, Web App, Hybrid Mobile App, UI Development, CMS Front-end Modules for school communications, religious education and eLearning.

# **Key Responsibilities**

- Leading and establishing technical direction and standards for front-end development;
- Providing guidance and support for all front-end development activities;
- Providing technical support and suggestions on digital design activities;
- Supporting management for sales activities (e.g. estimations, scope refinement);

# **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY (CONTINUED)**

# **Creative Designer**

FinPa New Media (JUL 2005 - APR 2011) Melbourne, AUSTRALIA

Worked on web, eLearning and multimedia resources across various industries.

#### **Roles and Responsibilities**

- Art direction and multimedia Lead
- Web design, Graphic design, UI design Accessibility and usability
- Flash design and animation
- Web standards

  - Character design

# **Senior Designer**

ETANG (DEC 2003 - JAN 2005) Shanghai, CHINA

Worked on marketing campaigns, communications, design and front-end development of etang.com - a major pioneer social media online community in China.

# **Roles and Responsibilities**

- Creating Banner ADs, EDMs
- Flash design and development
- Web design and front-end development
- UI design, character design

# Interactive Designer

From-Zero Interactive Solutions (JAN 2003 - SEP 2003) Shanghai, CHINA

Worked on microsites, websites and digital advertising campaigns for major local and international brands. (Adidas, L'Oréal, Siemens, Toshiba, etc.)

# **Roles and Responsibilities**

- Creating Banner ADs, EDMs
- Interaction and animation design
- Flash design and development
- Web design and front-end development

#### **EDUCATION**

# Master of Multimedia Design

Monash University (2005 - 2006) Melbourne, AUSTRALIA

Multimedia Design Theories and Techniques, Digital and Interaction Design, Business Practice for Multimedia Design

# **Bachelor of Artistic Design**

Shanghai Jiao Tong University (1999 - 2003) Shanghai, CHINA

Fine Art, Graphic Design, Visual Communication, Visual Identity, Fundamental Branding and Advertising Theories

## **Certificate of Animation**

Autodesk (2007) Sydney, AUSTRALIA

A 2-day Master Class held by Autodesk and Andrew Gordon from Pixar Animation Studios, on animation design and techniques.

# **AWARDS**

#### 2012 - 16th Annual Webby Awards Official Honouree

Together At One Altar

http://www.togetheratonealtar.catholic.edu.au

### 2006 - NEWWEBPICK (Flash Design and Technology)

Hunt Angels Official Movie Site

#### **INTERESTS & INSPIRATIONS**

Art, Design, Movies, Music, Video Games, Storytelling, Web and Technology, Photography, Food and Cooking

#### **LANGUAGES**

English (Fluent), Chinese (Native)

#### RECOMMENDATIONS

"During his time at Fraynework Johnny has proven to be a true leader in front-end development and has constantly risen to every challenge that has been thrown his way. Johnny has a terrific eye for detail and truly excels in the areas of interaction design, responsive web design and mobile web development. He also has a terrific work ethic and a curious nature, which has made him a delight to work with and a pivotal member of our team. In addition to completing all of his projects with a high level of quality and a minimum of fuss, Johnny has also provided leadership within the team and provided a great deal of assistance to other developers and designers and helped grow the capacity of the group."

# Steve Darmody Director of Interactive Media, Fraynework Limited

managed Johnny since 2011

"Johnny made animated banner ads and graphics for Oodles on a number of occasions. I found him to interpret the briefs with a creative mind set and thereby improving on the original concept. Also very timely and the quality of the finished artwork and graphics were always of high quality. I recommend Johnny to others seeking creativity, quality and value for money."

Steve Sherlock Founder, Oodles.com

hired Johnny as a Graphic/Web Designer in 2009

"I have worked with Johnny in the development of educational multimedia products. He is an outstanding designer and has a great ability to translate the client's design requirements and brief into the end design. I highly recommend him for creative design roles."

Rachel Kennedy The Le@rning Federation

hired Johnny as a Graphic/Web Designer in 2008

## **REFEREES**

Available upon request.